我们，是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文！
and Steven!
与洋葱头为友
翻译
零九/presisco
校对
BBBB
特效
CCCC
压制
DDDD
爽～！完美钟点午后三明治，达成！
Yes! Perfectly timed afternoon sandwich complete.
等下，我可不能单独吃如此完美的三明治
Wait, I can't eat such a perfect sandwich all on its own.
得有点配餐
It needs a side.
但用什么呢？
But what?
哦，嘿，紫晶，我做午餐了
Oh, hey, Amethyst. I made lunch.
你想吃空盒子吗？
You want to eat this empty container?
不，谢了
No, thanks.
O-okay.
你看到石榴或珍珠了吗？
You seen Garnet or Pearl?
没
Nope.
你猜她们可能在哪？
Any idea where they might be?
不知道
I don't know.
反正不是在相互交谈
Somewhere not talking to each other.
Hmm.
嗯，我知道需要什么了
Wait, I know what this meal needs.
一袋...
A bag of...
洋葱头？！
Onion?!
搞毛？
What the...
哦，不，你可别想
Oh, no, you don't.
洋葱头！
Onion!
我们才装上的纱窗！
We just put that screen in!
给我回来！
Come back here!
那得用来完成我的完美午餐！
Those were going to complete my perfect lunch!
可是特别口味啊，
It's a special flavor
限时供应的！
that's only in stores for a limited time!
我知道到你手里的食物的下场！
I know how you are with food!
你从来都不吃！
You're not even gonna eat them!
至少让我尝一口啊！
At least let me have just one!
啊哈，洋葱头，无处可躲了吧
This is it, Onion. Nowhere to hide.
现在放-放下零食和-
Now just -- just drop the bag and --
呃...洋葱头？
uh...Onion?
呃...
Uh...
紫晶？
Amethyst?
呃...这就有点诡异了！
Uh...That's really weird!
呃，所以...我一直清楚洋葱头有点怪，但...
Um, so...I always knew Onion was weird, but...
我感觉他对你有点那啥？
I think he's obsessed with you?
你觉得呢，紫晶？
What do you think, Amethyst?
谁在那里？
Who's in there?
好吧，我不知道你如何绕过油布的
Now, I don't know how you got past that tarp,
但这可是私人领地
but this is private property.
维达利亚？
Vidalia?!
紫晶？！
Amethyst?!
都多少年了！
It's been years!
天，你变了好多
Man, you've changed.
看起来糟透了！
You look terrible!
你还是一样...
You look the same...
遭！
Terrible!
等等，怎么了？
Wait, what?
她是谁？你们是怎么认识的？
Who's she? How do you know each other?
哦，我们都和你爸有交往，
Oh, we both kind of hung around your dad,
但维达利亚比你爸更酷，
but Vidalia's cooler than your dad,
所以我们便开始单独交往了
so we started hanging out without him.
那是史蒂文吧？看看
Is that Steven? Look at him.
长得和格雷格一模一样
He looks just like Greg.
没什么，没什么，他原来可帅了
That's good. That's good. He used to be super hot.
呃，所以你们原来在一起时画的这些？
Uh, so did you paint these when you used to hang out?
是啊，应该说是一部分，不过有些是新画的
Yeah, some of them. Some are new, though.
紫晶曾是我最喜欢的模特
Amethyst was my favorite model.
你仍然可以变成任何物体吧？
Can you still turn into anything?
当然，不过正经的不行
Anything but respectable.
此处紫晶的造型致敬毕加索的超现实立体派肖像画
哦，天哪，我们之前可惹过各种麻烦
Oh, man, we used to get into all sorts of trouble.
来告诉我，史蒂文
Now tell me, Steven,
我们算不算叛逆先锋？
aren't we just the spitting image of mischief?
勉强把
Hardly.
你怎么穿拖鞋了
You're wearing slippers.
你可猜不到我用这双鞋干过什么
You don't know what I've done in these shoes.
很高兴再次见到你
It's great to see you again.
对不起好久没联系了
Sorry it's been so long.
我猜我们都很忙吧
I guess we've both been busy.
哦，对啊，我知道-小孩嘛
Oh, yeah. I get it -- kids.
孩子怎么了？
What about kids?
噢，这就有个
Oh, here's one now.
你是洋葱头的妈妈？！
You're Onion's mom?!
没错
Yep.
他就是我的小捣蛋鬼
He's my little troublemaker.
而且，史蒂文，他很喜欢谈论你
And, Steven, he loves talking about you.
哦，那是个好主意！
Oh, that's a great idea!
史蒂文，紫晶，洋葱头想知道
Steven, Amethyst, Onion wants to know
你们愿不愿离留下吃晚餐
if you'd like to stay for dinner.
呃
Um
当然啦，
We'd love to,
对吧，史蒂文？洋葱头就像，你的好朋友
Right, Steven? Onion's, like, your best friend.
现在，该告诉我你穿着拖鞋做过什么了吧，妹子？
Now, tell me what you did in those shoes, girl.
我可没法再多塞一口
Mm, I can't eat another bite of
那种不可言状的玩意了
Whatever that was.
噢，那只是一道
Oh, it's just a little dish
我起名为奶油炒面条的菜
I like to call noodles and butter.
我简直不敢相信过了这么久
I can't believe how long it's been.
我是说，看看他
I mean, check this guy out.
我之前可是比他高的
I used to be bigger than him.
你之后有臭子马蒂的消息吗？
Do you ever hear from old farty Marty?
蛤？
Hm?
我可不知道那个笨蛋在哪
I don't know where that fool is.
也不在乎
Don't care, either.
之后一直是我和黄鳍在一起
It's just been me and Yellowtail for a while now.
啊？！
What?!
黄鳍？
Yellowtail?
没错，我们直接来了电
Yeah, things just kind of happened.
之后，我就和渔民在一起了
Next thing you know, I'm living with a fisherman.
你该看看你的表情
You should see your face right now.
嘿，酸奶油
Hey, Sour Cream.
我怎么猜得到？
I just didn't expect any of this.
好吧，事情现在就是这样
Well, that's just how it is now.
那么现在老鱼鳍在哪？
So where's old fish tail at?
呃，是“黄鳍”
Uh, it's Yellowtail.
黄鳍用土豆泥做雕像的镜头致敬斯皮尔伯格的电影《第三类接触》中的著名镜头
其中男主将土豆泥塑造成了自己喜欢的山脉的形状
他大部分时间在海上
He spends a lot of time out at sea.
嘿，那是我
Hey, it's me.
伙计，你之前可一直在抱怨
Dude, you used to complain so much
码头的那种味道
about the smell at the docks.
那里原来可恶心了
It used to be so gross over there.
现在那里
Now there are all these fancy boats hanging around.
还记得我们曾偷偷进入市长的船然后乱搞一气吗？
Remember when we snuck on to the mayor's boat and trashed it?
为什么你这么讨厌食物？
Why do you hate food?
对啊，我还记得
Yeah, I remember.
你呢，紫晶？
What about you, Amethyst?
呃？
Huh?
你一晚上还没说过你的故事呢
You haven't said a word about yourself all night.
其实，这是因为我的生活太无聊了
Well, that's because my life is boring.
好吧，宝石人们怎么样？
All right, how are the gems?
我不知道，她们也很无聊
I don't know. They're boring, too.
好吧，谢谢你们的晚安，该走了，不是吗，紫晶？
Okay, thanks for dinner. Time to go, right, Amethyst?
急什么集？我们又没事做
What's the hurry? We got nothing to do.
另，紫晶/维达利亚派对从不停止
'Sides, an amethyst/vidalia party don't end
除非太阳出来了
till the sun come up.
妈-妈
Ma-ma.
怎么了？
What's that?
妈妈妈妈-麻麻-嘛-码-码-嘛～
哦，那是个好主意！
Oh, that's a great idea!
史蒂文，洋葱头想带你看看屋子
Steven, Onion wants to show you around the house.
怎么样？让洋葱头带你看看？
What do you say? Can Onion tote you around?
呃..发..发生了什么？
Uh... W-what's going on?
哦，每当酸奶油开始打碟，
Oh, whenever Sour Cream starts deejaying,
就会用光整栋房的电力
it uses all the electricity in the house.
还好黄鳍不在家-
Good thing Yellowtail's not here --
这能逼疯他的
it drives him nuts.
伙计，你的房子嗨上天了
Dude, your house is jacked.
你能怎么办？孩子们要表现自我
What can you do? Kids got to express themselves.
你也是，洋葱头
You too, Onion.
相当有表现力
Very expressive.
看来他准备好了，史蒂文
Looks like he's ready for you, Steven.
呃...挺酷的购物车
Uh... Cool shopping cart.
洋葱头床头的海报致敬摇滚乐队The Door
为什么你不在蹦床上跳呢？
Why don't you just jump up and down on that trampoline?
我是说，就像，在那
I mean, it's, like, right there.
但这是你的房间...
But it's your room...
..那么随你便啦
...So do whatever you want.
你还有个小老鼠做室友！
You have a little mousy roommate friend!
嗷～
Aww!
哦
Oh.
那是你的宠物？
Is that your pet?
哦，他一定住那里，对吧？
Oh, that must be where he lives, right?
让我帮你将他放回家
Let me help you put him in his home.
这对小宝宝来讲真是个大箱-
This is a pretty large container for a little baby --
蛇！
snake!
洋葱头，你想让我Onion, you want me
用我们的小伙伴喂蛇吗？
to feed our little friend to this snake, huh?
哦
Oh.
对不起，但我们都得吃饭的
Sorry, but we all got to eat.
我...
I...
做不到！
Can't!
呃！赶紧把他从我手里拿走吧！
Ugh! Just take him from me!
我-我就在这里
I-I'll be over here.
呃...
Uh...
你不会再给我看更多的奇怪宠物了，对吧？
You don't have any more weird pets to show me, do you?
你要放电影？
You gonna put on a movie?
那真不错-一点也不怪异
That'd be nice -- and not creepy at all.
医院布景不错嘛
Cool hospital setting.
好的，我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready.
嘿，那是你妈妈
Hey, that's your mom.
我准备好了！
I'm ready!
她准备好做什么？
What's she getting ready for?
哦
Oh.
哦-黄鳍-我觉得...
Oh, Yellowtail, I think...
哦-他要出来了
Oh, it's happening!
呃，等下！发生了什么？！
Ugh, wait! What's going on?!
他来了！
Here he comes!
生日快乐，洋葱头
这是你出生的视频吗？！
Is this you being born?!
哦，我坚持不下去了-
Oh, I am never doing this --
我没法再承受了
I can't take much more of this.
这个很明显了，《肖申克的救赎》里的越狱隧道
哪里？
Where?
好吧，我得走了
Okay, I'm out.
不能再继续了，得回家了
Can't do this anymore. Need to go home.
紫晶，对不起，但是时候-
Amethyst, I'm sorry, but it's time to --
所有事都一团糟
Everything is a mess,
即使是石榴，就像，我从没见过石榴这么生气过
even Garnet, like, I've never seen Garnet this upset.
家里感觉非常遭，我感觉非常压抑
It's awful at home. I feel trapped.
那真是太夸张了，不过我知道你的意思
That's crazy. I know what you mean, though.
真的？
You do?
嘿，我们一家并不总是相处的非常愉快
Hey, we don't always get along in this family.
黄鳍和酸奶油总是相互掐架
Yellowtail and Sour Cream are always at each other's throats.
这让我非常苦恼
It makes me nuts.
实际上，每当我烦恼时，
Actually, when I get like that,
我总想到你
I think about you
还有你毫不在乎的态度
and how you could always just roll with it.
什么？！
What?!
不！就是你
No! That was you!
你当初是那么...酷
You were so...Cool.
我就像...一个跟着你的蠢海绵
I was just like...A dumb sponge following you around.
但你，遇事沉着，心无畏惧
But you were down for anything, not afraid of anything.
你知道我有多想变成你吗？
You know how much I wanted to be like you?
呃，我现在仍然这么认为
Ugh. I still think about it.
说实话，这也是为什么我再次开始画你的画像
To be honest, that's why I started painting you again.
我-我深受你的激励，紫晶
I'm -- I'm inspired by you, Amethyst.
哦，看来我得再泡一杯茶了
Oh, looks like I'm gonna need more tea.
你想吃了茶包吗？
You want to eat this bag?
当然啊，这可是最爱
Yeah, my favorite.
好的，我很快就回来
Okay, I'll be right back.
还好孩子们一直有事情做
Good thing the kids are keeping themselves busy.
好吧，洋葱头，继续吧
Okay, Onion, let's do this.
无论你准备了多么怪异或恐怖的东西，
Whatever weird or horrible thing you have planned for me,
我都能接住
I can take it.
嘿，慢点
Hey, slow down.
哦，天哪，这可不会有什么好结果
Oh, boy. This is gonna be bad.
此处画面的移动方式与周边游戏Attack the Light相同
呃，呃，洋葱头，你在哪？
Uh, uh, Onion, where are you?
这是什么房间？
What's this room?
洋葱头的秘密房间与位置是皮克斯总部内部酒吧的再现
哦！
Oh!
此处洋葱头的画像致敬《2001太空漫游》中的星孩
这里有什么？可怕的东西吗？
What's in there? Something horrible?
洋葱头！箱子里全是侠盗玩偶！
Onion! It's full of guys!
红色的忍者侠盗致敬洛克人2中的Quickman
喔～
Wow!
我从没见过红色的忍者侠盗啊
I've never seen this red variant of ninja guy before.
你还有女侠？！
You have gals, too?!
安全帽女侠！
Hard hat gal!
三角女侠！
Triangle gal!
粉色三角为同性恋同性恋斗争的标志
橘子女侠！
Orange gal!
凯伦！
Karen!
看起来像不像Rebecca Sugar（糖姐）？
凯伦...
Karen...
你是怎么收集到-不，别告诉我
How'd you get a hold of -- no, don't tell me.
嗯？
Hmm?
不可能吧！
No way!
这是探险女侠！
It's explorer gal!
她看起来可酷了！
She's so cool-looking!
谢谢你让我看看她-
Thanks for showing her to me --
你-你应该收回你的探险女侠
you -- you should take your explorer gal back.
你是要送给我吗？
Are you giving this to me?
我简直不敢相信！
I can't believe it!
太感谢你了，洋葱头！
Thank you so much, Onion!
嗷，天哪！你还有什么侠盗和女侠？！
Aw, man! What other gals and guys you got?!
哈，太酷了-隐身侠盗
Ha, cool -- invisible guy.
你们可以走啦
And stay out.
呃，谢谢你们的晚餐-和倾听
Um, thanks for dinner -- and for listening.
当然，也谢谢你们闯进我家
Well, thanks for breaking into my house.
同时不要担心那件事
And don't worry about that other stuff.
那迟早会过去的
It's gonna blow over.
你是块石头
You're a rock.
不是吗？
That's what you are, right?
呃，差不多吧
Uh, something like that.
那么，不论你是什么，一定不要见外啊
Well, whatever you are, don't be a stranger.
当然，我随时可以来，只要你需要-
Yeah, I can stop by anytime if you need,
灵感
inspiration.
或者如果你需要，
Or if you want,
你也可以偶尔来神庙看看
you could come over to the temple sometime, too.
你也可以带上洋葱头来和史蒂文玩
You could even bring Onion for Steven to hang with.
哦，当然，这听起来不错
Oh, well, that sounds great to us.
你呢，史蒂文？
What about you, Steven?
你准备好和他再来一局吗？
You ready for another round with this guy?
当然啦，改天见
Yeah, we'll see.
你
♪ You
爱，如你
♪ love like you